# Yogesvaran Saithu

C-1-08, Sri Pandan Condominium, Pandan Mewah, 68000 Ampang, Kuala Lumpur yogesvaran.saithu@gmail.com +6012-636 7975

# **WORK SUMMARY**

A Group Finance Manager with 17 years working experience in various industries such as IT, Oil & Gas, Heavy Lifting, Maritime, Port Services, Telecommunication, Venture capital & private equity, Media & broadcasting. Able to handle a finance team, cash flow management, budgeting, management reporting, and tax planning, reviewing and analysing financial report with ratio and variance analysis. Worked with diverse group of investors, business partners, directors, auditors, bankers (USA, Norway, India, Singapore & Indonesia)

# **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

To be successful in Finance and Accounting and to excel in the field of Management in a fast paced and forward thinking company in which my abilities and qualifications can be challenged and expanded.

# **EDUCATION**

| 1998-2000 | University of Western Sydney (Hawkesbury Australia)<br>Bachelor of Commerce (majoring in accounting) |
|-----------|--|
| 1995-1997 | Northern Territory University (Australia)<br>Diploma in Accountancy                                  |
| 1994-1995 | St Paul's Institution- Seremban<br>Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia  |

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Schlumberger

#### Schlumberger (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd

Schlumberger is the world's leading supplier of technology, integrated project management and information solutions to customers working in the oil and gas industry worldwide. Schlumberger Malaysia contributes to the local knowledge, innovation and teamwork in developing the hydrocarbon industry.

Position held : Management Accountant Location : Bandar Utama, Kuala Lumpur

Period : Jan 2016 – todate (contract end by November 2017)

Responsibilities:

- Prepares financial analysis and reports for review, to assist decision-making and planning.
- Prepares, reconciles and reviews balance sheet notes, including sub systems, and participates in follow-up actions.
- Prepares monthly end financial activities.
- Prepares and analyses profit and loss accounts including reviews of revenue and cost transactions.
- Provides profit and loss analysis for bid planning purposes.
- Meets deadlines, and ensures quality of deliverables to ensure KPI objectives are met.
- Participates in ad hoc reporting, analysis and projects.



## **CISCO Systems Malaysia**

CISCO Systems is a worldwide IT leader. CISCO founded on 1984 in San Francisco, California. CISCO has become the worldwide leader in networking, transforming how people connect, communicate and collaborate

Position held : Finance Manager

Location : KL Sentral, Kuala Lumpur Period : Dec 2014 – Sept 2015

#### Responsibilities:

- Prepare and disseminate timely and accurate financial information. Generating reports, analyses and models as requested by the business to support the overall process regionally and globally
- Perform scenario analysis & planning to be used for decision making and approvals.
- Disseminate Organizational Expense & HC reporting, Bookings, Revenue and Margin Analysis for APJ region
- Acting as the primary contact to designated business finance partner providing timely advice & appropriate reporting & analysis thereon
- Assisting in providing value-added management decision support, driving key business goals, identify major trends and corresponding business issues



#### **Ranchan Group of companies**

Ranchan Group focuses on Oil & gas, Maritime, Heavy Lifting, Port Services and Information technology projects. RGC is an ISO certified. RGC involved in major turnkey projects with Bumi Armada, VALE Minerals, Tanjung Pelepas Port (PTP), Penang Port, North Port, West Port and UMW Synergistic. RGC is diversified

Position held : Group Finance Manager Location : Subang Jaya, Selangor Period : Sept 2011 – Nov 2014

## Responsibilities:

- Manage full spectrum of finance, treasury including maintaining effective financial planning, budgeting and forecasting and cash flow management.
- Preparation of group financial statement.
- Assist on yearly audit and tax preparation and other statutory reporting.
- Involved in GST implementation, Reviewing project contracts, Fund raising for projects
- Assist Group GM on weekly report submission, KPI on Group performances.



#### All Asia Broadcast Network (ASTRO)

Astro is owned and operated by *MEASAT Broadcast Network Systems*, a wholly owned subsidiary of Astro Holdings Sdn Bhd, a company owned by Usaha Tegas Sdn Bhd/its affiliates, and Khazanah Nasional Berhad. Astro is the brand name of the Malaysian direct broadcast satellite (DBS) pay television service. It transmits digital satellite television and radio to households in Malaysia & Brunei. Astro's international operation and joint venture includes *Kristal astro-* Brunei, *Astro Nusantara-*Indonesia, *Sun direct DTH-* India.

Position held : Assistant Manager Finance & Administration

Location : Bukit Jalil, Kuala Lumpur Period : July 2010 – May 2011

### Responsibilities:

- Manage the accounting and finance functions of the Group in compliance with existing policies and procedures and regulatory requirements.
- Preparation of financial reports (month end closing), group accounts consolidation, forecast, project budgets, variance analysis, cost allocation.
- Review monthly financial statements (balance sheet, P&L and cash flow statements), budget, forecast, variance analysis. Involved in quarterly KPI presentation for each business unit.
- Liaise with parties including external auditors and bankers on financial information
- Assists the Head of Department in developing basis/ estimation for the computation of margins, cost allocation etc.
- Supervise, monitor, train accounting staff.
- Oversee and manage the inter company and related party transaction analysis



#### MRY Associates Sdn Bhd

MRY Associates involved in latex gloves, agricultural green bio technology, private equity, consulting and medical prototype industry. MRY is a latex and synthetic glove specification developer, processor, exporter and boutique operation. Its manufacturing facility is ISO9002, ISO 13488 and En 46002 certified. It's an innovative company with product development that is ahead of the industry curve.

Position held : Finance Manager

Location : Mont Kiara, Kuala Lumpur Period : Sept 2005 – June 2010

#### Responsibilities:

- Prepare statutory financial reports for Malaysia and foreign entities.
- Perform month-end financial reporting, prepare budget, forecast, review and recommendations on variance analysis and monitor controls so that accurate and timely financial information is available for statutory and management accounts.
- Maintain key controls that safeguard the assets of the Group
- Liaise with parties including external auditors and bankers on financial information
- Prepare such financial information as required for submission to the tax authorities to ensure local tax laws are complied with and obligations reported on a timely basis.
- Prepare 12 month running cash flow forecasts for MRY and its associate companies
- Any other duties related to the successful financial management of the Malaysia office



### **Intelligent Capital Sdn Bhd**

Intelligent Capital involves in (providing proprietary and third party funds to promising technology companies at varying stages of growth from start up to mezzanine-including pre-IPO, providing corporate advise on funding strategy, arranging for funding, capital market access, mergers and acquisitions, restructuring, and selection of and negotiation with investors)

Position held : Accountant

Location : Mont Kiara, Hartamas, Kuala Lumpur

Period : July 2001 –August 2005

### Responsibilities:

- Preparation of periodic financial statements, budget and forecast, cash flow projections. Review and analyse financial report with ratios and variance analysis.
- Review, suggest and implement improvement in accounting system, internal controls and policies.
- Experience in external reporting (Indonesia, India and Norway)
- Manage Investor Portfolio Capital Accounts and venture capital investments worth 5 to 50 million.
- Involved in feasibility studies, due diligence & evaluate new investment proposal and policies
- Liaise with external auditors, tax consultants on tax planning and submission, securities commission and government bodies (EPF, SOCSO, Statistics Dept).
- Exposure in Venture Capital and Private Equity, stock market trades and maintaining share trading accounts.



## **CM Power Electrical Engineering**

CM Power is an M & E provider based in Puchong Selangor. It involved in telecommunication mobile coverage, infrastructure fabrication and Mobile Integration and Commissioning. CM Power was working on mobile integration projects with several telecommunications provider such as maxis mobile, DiGi and Celcom.

Position held : Senior Accounts Executive

Location : Puchong, Selangor Period : Jan 1998 – June 2001

Responsibilities:

- Involved in setting up proper accounting system, maintained full set of accounts and successfully reduced 30 hours a week of manual paper work.
- Involved in preparing cash flow, balance sheet and Profit & Loss
- Involved in Telecommunications project tenders, financial project management and project costing

# **SUMMARY OF SKILLS**

## **Computing Skills**

Microsoft Office, SAP System, Oracle System, Accounting packages (MYOB, UBS, FACT, Quick Book), Project Management

## **Accounting Skills**

Familiar with International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS), Malaysian Accounting Standard (MASB) and Company Act 1965. Sound accounting and economics knowledge through studies in university and gained experience hands on experiences in different companies.

REFERENCES will be provided upon request.